残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても
私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっと触れるもの 求めることに夢中で
運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の訂正 窓辺からやがて届く
ほとばしる熱いパトスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
マジョー・カツアラギ メチューマジョー・カツアラギ
微笑んでいた dryer 雰囲として あなたの体重に
can understand our thought patterns is completely unknown a new factor has been revealed in this
incident in that the angel tried to take ava into itself is there any possibility that this aspect
may be linked to the predicted 13th angel and all angels thereafter based on the previous patterns
we've observed there would appear to be no systematic organization among the angels correct
they have worked independently thus far what do you mean sir you may not ask questions understood
that will be all dismissed yes sir well what do you think ikari the angels appear to be getting
more intelligent there's not much time left left for us you mean who's the patient in room 12. that's
the emergency room patient from the first ava incident she's been here for a long time her injuries are
really complicated poor girl and she's still in elementary school he's here again today yeah
he comes to see her at least twice a week he's a good brother thinking about his sister like that
yeah boys like that are pretty rare
ray are things satisfactory yes i will be with dr akagi all day tomorrow and the day after that i
will be in school and how is school no problem sir i see that's good class attention okay sit down
well ayanami is absent as usual and so is mr ida hey what's up with kinsuke he's in new yokosuke
to see some dumb battleship ship called miyoko or something like that is important mr susahara
yes sir will you deliver this document to miss ayanami after school yes sir
the first branch is still okay no no don't bother the data from the recon sap still being confirmed
by the magi right it disappeared the entire second branch just vanished yes sir it's been confirmed
it's been wiped off the map oh my god i had second insect have gone crazy general affairs is total
chaos what do you think happened over there it's under investigation our only clues are these recon
photos from the geosynchronous satellite there's nothing else left ten seconds nine eight seven six five
four three two one contact
this is horrible evangelion unit four its support group and all the other facilities within an 89
kilometer radius were completely destroyed along with thousands of people looking at the time
schedule it would appear that they were in the middle of installing the experimental s2 unit from
germany potential causes range from an insufficient structural integrity to an error in calculation
during the preliminary design stage that's thirty two thousand seven hundred sixty eight possibilities
and that's not mentioning sabotage but it wasn't really an explosion was it it just disappeared
in all probability they were swallowed by a dirac c just as unit one was then they restored s2
engine is gone along with our hopes we're being forced to use things we don't understand
yes things like the avas so what do we do with unit three it's being shipped here as we speak the u.s
government doesn't want to risk losing their first branch as well didn't they insist on the right to
build units three and four in the first place and now they're forcing it off on us they're really
pushing it well you can't blame them can you after a disaster like that anyone would get nervous
we'll handle it and how are you going to handle the test activation will you use ray's dummy plug i'll
decide soon this is the dummy plug prototype ray's personal data has been transferred into it but
our current technology can't really digitize a human-minded soul in the end this is nothing but a pale
duplication that emulates the real pilots thinking processes it's still only a machine it transmits a
signal pattern to the ava if the ava believes that there is a pilot and synchronizes then that's
good enough load the data into units one and two but we're still working out the bugs sir just do it
it's sufficient yes sir
i've delegated the transport of the unit to the un it will be here by the end of the weekend at that time
you will take care of it yes sir we'll perform the modifications and activation test in matsushiro
and the test pilot use of the dummy plug is not recommended one of our candidates and will be
chosen as the fourth yes sir there is one child available whose core can be prepared immediately
then make it so yes sir ray we're finished now right let's eat yes stand up dismissed
yeah lunchtime at last my very favorite part of the entire school day what
what do you mean you didn't make our lunches i didn't have time to cook last night i had too
much homework oh you did did you and that's your excuse for me having to go without lunch uh-oh
the newlyweds are fighting oh shut up what's with the grim face uh well it's the unit three
activation test we'll be using the fourth as the test pilot the fourth the fourth child's been found
yesterday i haven't received a report from the marduk institute don't worry major you'll get your report
dr okagi are you hiding something from me again no of course not well okay so who's the kid
you're kidding him yes well the prospective candidates have to be kept together for their
own protection it can't be helped i don't know how to tell them it's hard asuka will be fine she's
committed to piloting an ava and ray is exceptional we've never had any problems with her shinji on the
other hand has gone through some pretty bad phases even depression i don't want to expose them to any
more stress i know but gathering children of this kind is an imperative it's for the sake of our own
survival you shouldn't shouldn't complicate things of course class dismissed bye
hey don't forget that you've got bulletin duty this week susahara i've got what the class bulletin
remember you're supposed to deliver this to miss ayanami oh come on who else has duty it's you and ayanami
this week it's ayanami and me then i guess i got it huh i can't go to some girl's place by myself
well i can go with you hey shinji welcome with me will you you know where ayanami lives right
hey ray i'm coming in hey you can't enter a girl's place without her permission we've got no
choice she won't see it if we leave it here uh is anybody home
my god this is a girl's room it's so decrepit
you shouldn't touch anything she'll get pissed i'm just cleaning up
well i won't help you do it it's just not manly well okay but you know misado hates guys like that
huh i don't care it's my policy all right
you know now that i think about it you've changed what you shinji
the first time i saw you i really thought you were the world's biggest jerk i mean
you sure didn't seem like someone who'd do something for someone else back then
i guess you were so deep in your shell that i couldn't see the real you
uh hi excuse us what for we brought you your school bulletins
i'm sorry i kind of cleaned up it was just trash right
thank you
man you ava pilots sure are a bunch of wackos huh
thank you words of gratitude words i've never used
not even with him
the city paradise made by mankind driven from paradise man escaped to this earthly existence on
the edge of death created by the weakest of beings created by the sapience born from that weakness
this paradise is our creation to protect ourselves from the fear death instills to satiate our beings
with pleasure we created a paradise by and of ourselves the city surely is such a paradise the city
designed and built to protect us a city for those who run in fear from the outside world the world of
our enemies of course cowards do tend to live longer that's one benefit the third new tokyo nerves hidden
intercept base and now the long delayed seventh construction phase is about to be finished at last
it's almost complete
now about unit four's accident how will you present that to the committee
with the facts the cause is unknown
but this was a major catastrophe
it was of no consequence to us the s2 engine sample may have been lost but the data is still in
germany this installation and unit one will be sufficient but the committee is in a total panic
of course they're panicked it wasn't scheduled yes zele must be busy rewriting their schedules now
incidents not depicted in the dead sea scrolls may occur this should teach the old men a lesson
the third district transformation and directional weapon experiment will be held as scheduled the
intercept system is completed and they're not going to have any party for it nerve has got to be the
most inflexible and stifling organization on earth well it's because of commander akari and are you
approved too i don't think that's pertinent data sir and i'm going to have to tell major katsuragi and
dr akagi about this not if i cover your mouth with mine kaji how's it going uh well it's going i guess
oh i have work to do excuse me far be it for me to make judgments on your private life but under the
current situation is it wise to be hitting on girls who are under certain chains of command who's under
who's not your concern would you prefer to be hit on that depends on how you answer this you know the
secrets behind the marduk institute and that adam thing right what secrets don't play games asking for
help isn't like yumi sato well i'm asking kaji something stinks here the way the fourth child was
found was too convenient something funny is going on i'll tell you one thing the marduk institute
doesn't exist nervous pulling the strings all by itself nerves pulling the strings commander ikari
707 is a good starting place code 707 but isn't that shinji's school misado yes ritsuko says
she's expecting you for a meeting about tomorrow's trip all right thank you i'll see you later
so can i buy you a drink cup o tea kaji i'm a boy
i thought you'd be a more serious person kaji you're saying that to someone as straight arrow and
reliable as me mr ikari i i'm sorry i'm sorry too i didn't mean to sound rude hey i want to show you
something
you grow melons yeah aren't they cute this is my hobby but keep it a secret okay
making something grow is really great one can see and learn so many things from the process
it also brings pleasure but pain too right
do you hate pain i i don't like it ah but have you found what gives you pleasure
that's not so bad if you've known pain and hardship it's easier to be kind to others
being kind isn't a weakness
uh hello yes
it's katsuragi the sink test will be starting soon
i was afraid of this shinji's sink ratio is dropping and what's that mean i can't say for sure
but i think that something may have happened to him during that last
incident something's affected him this makes it even harder to tell him about the pilot
well the new pilot will be informed officially tomorrow
stories
everyone stand up
Toji Suzuhara, report to the principal's office.
What? What'd you do now?
I don't know.
Excuse me, I'm Toji Suzuhara.
You're Toji Suzuhara?
How was your trip to New Yokosuka?
Oh, it was way cool.
Speaking of which, I did pick up some disturbing information.
AVA Unit 3?
Yeah, the one they build in the U.S.
It's been completed, hasn't it?
I don't know.
I know it's classified, but come on.
You gotta tell me something.
But I really don't know.
Haven't you heard the rumor that the activation test
will be held at the second test facility in Matsushiro?
No, I hadn't.
Then the pilot hasn't been chosen yet?
How would I know?
Misato could choose me for the position.
Shinji, would you ask her for me?
I really want to be an AVA pilot!
I don't know if she could or not.
Hmm.
Well, what about the story that Unit 4 was lost?
Was lost?
You really didn't know?
It disappeared along with the entire second branch.
My dad's whole section was in a panic.
Are you sure?
I've got my sources.
Misato didn't tell me anything.
Uh, well, you know, I guess it doesn't directly concern the pilots.
If she didn't tell you, it's probably because you don't need to know.
I'm sorry about bothering you with all these weird questions.
Hasn't Toji come back yet?
Thus, we, mankind, survived the hell called Second Impact and rose again.
The number of children have been decreasing on a year-to-year basis.
Uh, sorry, I'm late.
I know about it.
Be seated.
Anyway, it is you, the younger generation, who will lead the way to the future.
Let's get out of here.
Antoji?
Oh, he's going to be here late.
He's got clean-up duty today.
The school is now closing.
All students must go to their homes immediately.
Um, Zuzahara?
Huh?
You're on clean-up duty.
You have to line up these desks and clean off the blackboards.
No, I haven't had lunch yet.
I'll do it as soon as I've eaten.
Do you always buy your lunch from the school shop?
Well, of course.
There's no one at home who can cook.
Zuzahara?
Uh.
Hmm?
I have two sisters.
Their names are Kadami and Nozomi.
And I always make lunches for them every day.
That's a lot of work.
I am actually a pretty good cook, though I guess you might not expect that.
Hmm?
And you see, I always end up cooking too much for our lunches.
Well, that's definitely a waste.
If you need help getting rid of the leftovers, I'll help.
Oh, yes, please.
Hiya, Kaji.
Oh, Asuka.
Sorry, I'm busy right now.
Can it wait?
Don't you have time for Misato?
Kaji!
Dammit!
Not right now.
Hmm.
Oh, these are our sync data reports.
Huh?
Four?
Oh, my God.
It can't be.
Who in the hell made him the fourth child?
I won't stand for it.
I love it.
Fly me to the moon and let me play amongst the stars.
And let me see what spring is like on Jupiter and my.
The other world hold my hand.
The other world, baby.
It's me
Fill my heart with songs
And let me sing
Forevermore
You are all I long for
All I worship
And adore
In other worlds
Please be true
I love you
In other worlds
AVA Unit 3 is delivered to the testing facility, but the peaceful dog will soon be broken by dark clouds of disaster.
It is a time of tragedy, and the children will be at the focus of it.
The true nature of the beast inside will be revealed in the next horrifying episode.